すべては大いなる存在の
手のひらの上か…
I'll always be watching you from your shadows.
私はいつでもあなたの影から
見ていますからね
Hello?
はい
Evening! It's your favorite florist!
ありがとうございます
ごひいきの花屋です
What do you want, Colonel?!
なんのご用です  大佐
Sorry about that.
いや  すまん
I was a bit drunk and ended up buying a lot of flowers.
酔っ払って
花を大量に買ってしまってね
I'd be grateful if you'd be willing to take a few off my hands.
少し処分してくれると
有り難いのだが
What's wrong?
どうした
Did something happen?
何かあったのか
No, it's nothing.
いえ  何も
Are you sure?
本当か
Yes, it's nothing.
なんでもありません
I'll have to kindly refuse the flowers.
花は結構です
I don't own a vase to put them in.
うちには花瓶はありませんから
But thank you for giving me a call. Good night.
わざわざ声を掛けていただき
ありがとうございます  では
Why does he have such good timing when it comes to things like these?
なんでこういうタイミングは
いいのかしらね
Can't focus. My body is still puzzled about what to do.
集中できてないな　まだ体が迷っているんだ
Shuuchuu dekitenaina mada karada ga mayotteirunda
I'm trembling. I can't stop even if I try to control myself.
震えていたんじゃ　コントロールしたってブレるんだ
Furueteitanja kontoroorushitatte burerunda
Although neither sun nor moon are on my side,
ツキ
太陽も勝負運もなんも完全にこっち向いていないが
Taiyou mo tsuki mo nanmo kanzen ni kocchi muiteinaiga
"I've no choice but to try,"
「やるしかないんだ」
Yarushikanainda
Those were the words I muttered to myself.
言い聞かせるようにそうつぶやいた
Iikikaseruyouni sotto tsubuyaita
The odds aren't on my side, but running way'd be gutless.
状況は悪いが　ただ逃げ出すんじゃ根性ないなぁ
Joukyou wa waruiga tada nigedasunja konjou nainaa
Even if I can't see the future, I'll just have to win it over with courage.
展望はないが　度胸でクリアするしかないや
Tenbou wa naiga dokyou de kuria suru shika naiya
Need to keep distance from the target as I hold myself back.
衝動は抑えたままターゲットとの間隔探れ
Shoudou wa osaetamama taagetto to no kankaku sagure
All that's needed for victory is pride to win.
必要なもんは勝つプライド
Hitsuyou na mon wa katsu puraido
Will we celebrate with the wine of victory
味わうのは勝利の美酒か
Ajiwau nowa shouri no bishu ka
Or'll we end up kissing their feet in defeat?
それとも敗北の苦汁か
Soretomo haiboku no kujuu ka
There are two outcomes to everything.
そう　すべては2つに1つ
Sou subete wa futatsu ni hitotsu
I want to control destiny.
操りたい運命の糸
Ayatsuritai unmei no ito
I need to seize the golden opportunity with my hands.
絶好のゴールデンタイム　この手で掴め
Zekkou no goorudentaimu kono te de tsukame
I'll finish it up with my best poker face,
渾身のポーカーフェイス　キメて仕掛けるよ
Konshin no pookaafeisu kimete shikakeruyo
And drag them into a world of illusions.
イリュージョンの世界へ引きずり込んで
Iryuujon no sekai e hikizurikonde
I'll find my way out of this endless pressure game,
際限無いプレッシャーゲーム　スルリと抜けて
Saigennai puresshaageemu sururito nukete
And leap over the borderline of honor.
栄光のボーダーライン　飛び越えるために
Eikou no boodaarain tobikoeru tameni
How many? What'll I need to sacrifice to make it happen?
ハウメニー？　どれくらいの代償がいる？
Haumenii? Dorekurai no daishou ga iru?
What is the one thing I don't want to let go?
手放したくないもんはどれ？
Tebanashitakunai mon wa dore?
A man thought to be Scar was sighted on a mountain trail near the area.
近くの山道で
スカーらしき男が目撃された
We should start here.
向かうとしたら  ここだろう
An abandoned mine?
廃鉱ですか
That's right.
そうだ
This town, Baschool, is now a ghost town.
ここバズクールは  今は
ゴーストタウンになっている
It would make a great hideout.
隠れるには申し分ない
How troublesome.
厄介ですね
So we're going to split up.
だから  手分けして捜す
If a party spots him, report back immediately.
各部隊  スカーを見つけたら
すぐにこちらへ連絡を回すように
Roger!
はっ
We'll accompany the Elric Brothers.
エルリック兄弟には
我らが同行いたします
Yeah, yeah.
へいへい
I wonder if they're coming to keep an eye on us.
僕たちの見張りかな
Most likely.
おそらくな
Now...
さて
How should we get rid of these two...
どうやってこいつらをまこうか…
Hey! I just saw a shadow!
今  人影見えた
What?!
何っ
Over here!
こっち  こっち
Hey! Hang on!
ちょっと待て
Hey! Wait!
こら  待て
They disappeared!
いない
Where did they go?!
どこ行った
そっちの部屋に入ったんじゃないか
Did they go into that room?!
Damn them, running around!
くそ  ちょろちょろと
We were able to get rid of them, but...
なんとか…
うまく  まいたが…
...this place...
しかし  これは…
...is a bit...
...too big, don't you think?!
広すぎだぁ
Where are Scar and that little girl?
スカーも  あの子も
どこにいるんだろう…
If they don't randomly show up,
it'll be impossible for us to find them...
こりゃ 向こうから出てきてくれねぇと
捜すのはとても…
Sir Alphonse!
アルフォンス様
Sir Alphonse!!!
Hey!
おい…
No way...
まさか
Sir Alphonse!
アルフォンス様
She really showed up...
マジで来た…
What are you doing here?!
こんな所で
何をしてるんですか
May!
メイ  よかった  ほんとに会えた
Great! I found you!
Don't tell me... you came here looking for me?
まさか  アル様  私を追って
Yeah! I wanted to see you!
君に会いたかった
ズッキュン
Sir Al...
アル様…
I wanted to see you and learn more about Eastern Alchemy...
君に会って
錬丹術のことを詳しく…
どうしよう  夢かしら…
Oh my gosh! Am I dreaming? Sir Al came looking for me?
って  あれ
Huh?
アル様が私を…
Hey, brat!
おうおう 小娘
I've been dying to see you!
会いたかったぜぇ
I'm not letting you get away this time!
もう逃がさん
とっととお前の錬丹術を教えやがれ
Hurry up and teach us Eastern Alchemy!
You brothers are feuding for my hand!
兄弟で私を巡って略奪愛
ダメよ  エドワードさんは
But you're not my type, Edward!
私の好みじゃないもの
Don't play dumb with me!
とぼけてんじゃねぇ
Hey, Al...
ちょっと  アル…
Oh, sorry about that.
ごめん  ごめん
Ow...
あ痛たたっ…頭  打った
I hit my head.
Who is that woman, Sir Alphonse?!
なんですか  アルフォンス様  その女
How horrible... You have me, and yet...
ひどいわ  アル様
私という者がありながら…
No! She's just an old friend of mine!
いや
この子は単なる幼なじみで…
Wait... Why am I talking like a two-timer?
って  なんで  二股かけてる
男みたいな言い訳を…
May, please don't run off by yourself-
メイちゃん  あまり
一人で先に行っちゃダメ…
The Elric Brothers?!
エルリック兄弟
Who are you?
誰
It's me, Marcoh.
私だ  私  マルコーだ
Dr. Marcoh?!
マルコーさん
What happened to your face?
その顔  どうして…
What are you doing here?
君たちこそ  どうしてここに
The Elric Brothers!
エルリック兄弟
Who the heck are you?
誰だよ
Don't you dare say you forgot!
忘れたとは言わさんぞ
I'm Yoki, the great coal-mine owner of Youswell!
このユースウェルの偉大なる炭鉱主
ヨキ様のことを
忘れた
Guess I forgot.
Actually, I don't even think I know you.
つか  お前なんざ知らん
How awful! After all those things you did to me...
ひどい
あれだけのことをしておいて…
Youswell
Youswell, a mining town.
炭鉱の町  ユースウェル
I, Yoki, was a soldier and manager of the town.
私  ヨキはそこを治める
軍人兼炭鉱経営者であった
The people of the town lived happily due to my efforts.
私のお陰で  町の者どもは
幸せに暮らしていた
Hurry up and pay
your taxes!
We can't because you keep cutting our salaries!
And that's where the uttermost villain,
Edward Elric, a State Alchemist, showed up!
そこへ
突如現れた希代の極悪人
国家錬金術師
エドワード·エルリック
Silver pocketwatch!?
State Alchemist!!
Gold!!
I want to buy the rights to the coal mine with this
But it was a trap!
だがそれは巧妙な罠だったのだ
What is this about, Mr. Alchemist?!
All the gold I received from you turned into rocks!
They were working together!
なんと  ヤツらは
裏でつながっていたのである
And I, who had the mine stolen from me...
こうして
炭鉱をだまし取られた私は
...suffered at the hands of the people who forgot what they owed me...
恩を忘れた町の住民どもに
ひどい目に遭わされ
...and was given a bad name by the military.
軍部にはあらぬ汚名を着せられた…
I started many businesses in order to return to popularity...
再起を図り
各地で事業を展開したが…
...but it all ended in failure...
すべて失敗
My investments...
頼みの投資も…
...also ended in failure...
すべて失敗
And my last resort...
最後の手段
...was to ask a millionaire for a goodwill loan...
大富豪に善意の融資を
求めに行ったのだが…
If only...
あいつらさえ…
If only it hadn't been for those Elric Brothers...
エルリック兄弟たちさえ
いなければ…
And that was when I swore...
そのとき  私は誓った
Swore to take revenge against those two who brought me down like this.
そうだ  復讐してやる
この私をこんな目に遭わせた
あいつらに
An act of revenge far worse than death!
死よりも恐ろしい復讐を
I won't lose to a thief like you!
私  あなたみたいな泥棒猫に
絶対負けませんことよ
No... I'm not really a thief...
いや  あの…泥棒猫って…
だから  僕たちはなんでもないんだって
I'm telling you, there's nothing between us!
つうか  早く錬丹術のことをだな…
Who cares! I need to ask you about Eastern Alchemy!
Hey! How about you two listen to me?!
って  お前ら  話聞け
Yeah, whatever. It must have been hard, old man.
はいはい
つらかったなぁ  おっさん
分かるよぉ  その気持ち
I totally understand how you feel.
Quit pretending like you were listening!
適当に合わせてんじゃねぇ
You can't find Miss Winry?
ウィンリィさんがいない
Seriously... what were you all doing?
まったく  何をやっているのですか
We're terribly sorry...
すみません…
I'll go look for her.
私が捜そう
Two men from Charlie squad come with me.
チャーリー隊から２人ついてこい
Yes, sir!
はい
Major Miles.
マイルズ少佐
I know. Scar, right?
分かっている  スカーだろ
I'll contact you if I find him.
そちらも見つけしだい連絡する
This place is no good either, huh?
ここもダメか
There's barely anything here.
ろくなものがないな
You're Scar, right?
スカーだな
Sir Kimblee would like to see you.
キンブリー様がお待ちだ
Come with us.
我々と一緒に来てもらおう
I'm surprised you were able to find me.
随分と鼻が利く  だが
But do you really think the two of you can take me?
たった二人で  オレを
どうにかできると思っているのか
Probably not, if we were ordinary humans.
まあ  並の人間では無理だろう
If  we were ordinary humans, that is!
並の人間ならな
Chimeras, huh...
合成獣か…
Interesting!
おもしろい
I've learned a lot since then.
あれからいろいろ知ったよ
First, the method to create a philosopher's stone.
まず  賢者の石の作り方
Second, the history of this country. And that there's something odd about the alchemy this country uses.
そして  この国の成り立ち
錬金術がおかしいこと
That's why we came after this girl, seeking a possibility in Eastern Alchemy from Xing.
だからシンの国の錬丹術に
可能性を求めて
この子を追ってきた
Nothing less to be expected from you.
さすがだな
The thing is, someone realized it far before you did.
実は  そのことに
いち早く気づいた者がいた
These are the research documents he left us.
これは  その者が残した研究書だ
We think these documents may hold a clue to solving the mystery.
我々はこの書物に
解決の糸口があるとにらんでいる
So if we could decipher it...
じゃあ  そいつを読み解くことができれば…
Yes, possibly...
あるいは…
But to do that, we need Scar's help.
だが  それにはスカーの力が必要だ
Why him?!
なんで  あいつが…
What was that sound?
なんの音ですか
あそこはスカーがいる場所
That's where Scar went!
Could it be the army?!
軍の連中か
You four hide here.
ウィンリィとマルコーさんたちは
ここに隠れてろ
We'll go see what's going on.
オレとアルで様子を見てくる
Scar is...
スカーが…
ちっ  デブのくせに素早い
He's fat, but that doesn't slow him down at all!
I heard you're powerless unless you can actually touch us.
知ってるぞ  貴様
肉体に触れなければ
破壊できないんだろ
So we're going to be attacking from a distance.
この距離から
ネチネチと攻撃させてもらう
And we're also aware that you attempt to destroy the ground when things get bad for you.
状況が悪くなると
足もとを崩しにかかる癖も
リサーチ済みだ
We'll beat you to a pulp and hand you over to Sir Kimblee!
ズタボロにして
キンブリー様に渡してやるよ
おっとっと
Talk about good timing.
こりゃまたいいタイミングで
来ちゃったなぁ
The Elric Brothers?
エルリック兄弟か
This voice...
この声…
Brother, they're Kimblee's men from Central.
兄さん
こいつら  セントラルから来た
キンブリーの取り巻きたちだよ
What?
何
I get it...
なるほどね
You don't need to do anything besides watch.
そこでおとなしく見ていろ
We're going to capture Scar-
スカーは今我々が取り押さえ…
A monster!!!
ゲテモノ
ななっ  何をする  我々は味方…
W-What was that for?! We're on your sid-
こんな人間離れした味方なんて
I don't recall having any monsters on our side!
知りません
怖ぁ  味方の振りをして
How frightening!
They're going to pretend they're on our side, then eat us!
オレたちを食おうってんだぜ
後ろのデブも口でかいよ
The fat one back there has a really big mouth! He'll eat me whole!
僕  丸飲みされちゃうよ
このガキがおとなしくしてろ
You brat! Stay put!
おっと
Is he faster than Scar?!
こいつ  スカーより速くねぇか
Brother?
兄さん
What's so funny?!
何がおかしい
So light!
軽い  軽いぞ
It feels like my limbs are made of feathers!
手足がまるで羽のようだ
すばらしきかな  寒冷地用機械鎧
Northern automails are fabulous!
Don't get too cocky now...
おのれ  なめやがって…
ありゃ  パンチも軽くなってる
Huh? I guess my punches lost some force, too.
My spit won't come off that easily!
オレの唾液は簡単には取れんぞ
This is slob?! That's just gross!
よだれかよ  汚ぇ
くらえ
唾液ってことは…
In that case...
If I decompose it, it's pretty much water!
分解すりゃ  ほぼ水じゃねぇか
Th-That's cold!!
冷たい
Take this!
くらえ
What the heck was that for, Brother?!
何すんだよ  兄さん
O-O-Ow! Stop moving!
痛てててっ
やめろ 皮膚がはがれる
You're going to tear my skin off!
必殺
How did you like my "Touching Cold Metal With Wet Hands and Getting Stuck Together" attack?
「ぬれた手で冷えた金属に触ると凍りつくアタック」
Quit getting in our way, Fullmetal Alchemist!
邪魔をするな  鋼の錬金術師
お前はこっちの味方だろうが
Aren't you on our  side?!
うっせぇ  イノブタ
Shut up, pig! I don't know anyone who looks like you!
お前みたいなヤツ
知り合いにおらん
だいたい  どう見ても
Besides, anyone can tell you're a bad guy!
敵キャラだろうが
If you still insist that you're on our side, prove it!
味方だっつうなら
証拠見せろやぁ
Fine! I'll transform back, just watch!
今変身解くから
ちゃんと見てろ
I've been waiting for this!
このときを待っていたぜ
ザンパノ
Zampano!
How foolish of you to sheath
your sword in front of your enemy.
敵前で武器を収めるとは愚かな
Dammit! Get off me!
くそっ  離れろ  この
Okay, I'm going to need you to take a little nap.
はいはい  ちょっと寝ててね
He's in fighting shape, now...
復活しちまったよ
Hurry up and get caught already.
いいかげん  捕まっちまえよ
出るとこ出て
Face trial, Scar!
裁きを受けるんだ  スカー
I'll destroy whoever gets in my way.
邪魔する者は排除するのみ
He's coming head-on, without thinking?
何も考えず
まっすぐ突っ込んでくるとは…
Your steel arm is mine!
その鋼の右腕  もらうぞ
Sorry. It's not made out of steel anymore!
残念  もう鋼じゃねぇんだよ
Stay still!
おとなしく…
Stop it!
やめて
Idiot! Why did you come?!
バカやろう  なんで来た
Stay back.
下がっていなさい
マイルズ少佐
Major Miles.
Wh-What's up with these two?
なんだ  こいつら…
The people at Central seem to be conducting awful experiments.
セントラルの連中
とんでもない実験をしているようだな
Tie them to that pillar over there.
そこの柱へ縛っておけ
Aye, sir!
アイ  サー
Now, Scar...
さて  スカーよ
It doesn't please me to pass judgment on a fellow countryman, but I can't let someone like you run free.
同族を裁くのはつらいが
貴様のようなヤツを
のさばらせておくわけには
いかんのでな
Fellow countryman?
同族だと
Elric Brothers, we'll take care of the rest...
エルリック兄弟  あとは我々が…
Winry!
ウィンリィ
バカ  近寄るな
Idiot! Stay away from him!
Let me go... I'll be fine.
放して…大丈夫だから
大丈夫なわけあるか
How will you be fine?!
Stay away from him, Miss.
お嬢さん  離れていなさい
Please let me talk to him.
話  させてください
I want to talk to him face to face.
ちゃんと向かい合って
話がしたいの
Why did you kill my parents?
なんで
父さんと母さんを殺したの
No matter what I say, it'll be only be an excuse.
何を言っても
言い訳にしかならん
The fact is I killed the Rockbells.
オレがロックベルという
医者夫婦を殺したのは事実だ
What was that?!
何事か
It's in the location of the building we received a report from!
連絡のあったビルの方向です
This isn't good. We've been down here for more than twenty-four hours, which is what we promised.
まずいな
約束の２４時間を過ぎちまった
It's the Ice Queen we're talking about.
あの女王様のことだ
I'm sure she really sealed the exit.
本当に出口を封鎖してるだろうな
It's only natural we took so long.
しょうがないですよ
We groped our way here with the lanterns out, after all.
ランタン消して
手探りで進んだんですから
Since they insisted a monster would come if we kept the lights on.
「明かりをつけたら
化け物が来る」の
一点張りだったからな
Welcome back.
おかえりなさい
Thank goodness!
助かった
Take these two to the infirmary. Quickly!
二人を早く医務室へ
Sorry for the trouble...
すまない…
You have nothing to apologize for.
謝ることはない
I thought I told you to seal the exit after twenty-four hours?
２４時間たったら
穴をふさぐよう言ったはずだが
Ah. But, look.
はあ  でも  ほら
It hasn't been twenty-four hours yet.
まだ２４時間たっていないもんで
By the way, Major General Armstrong told me to go by this watch.
ちなみにこの時計ね
アームストロング少将が
くれたんだけどね
General!
閣下
Was the advance unit safe?
先遣隊は無事だったか
Just two of them.
なんとか  二人だけ
I see.
そうか
What are you doing here, if I may ask?
こんな所で何を
I was looking at the mountains.
山を見ていた
Winter is nice here, isn't it?
ここの冬はいいな
I only see black and white.
白と黒しかない
It's very plain, and I like it.
非常にはっきりしていて好きだ
Do you think so?
そうでしょうか
If you look up, there's also the color blue.
見上げれば  青もありますぞ
It's just like a person's heart, isn't it?
人の心と同じですな
この度はお情けをかけていただき
I greatly appreciate you giving us leeway this time, ma'am.
ありがとうございます
Huh? I have no idea what you're talking about.
さあ  なんのことか分からんな
Looks like we've got some guests.
何か来ましたな
It's been a while.
久しぶりだな
Sorry for asking this the moment of my arrival,
but is there something you owe us an explanation for?
早速で悪いが  何か我々に
申し開きせねばならないことが
あるのではないかね
Don't get too close!
近づくな
All men, stay back!
全員  下がれ
くそっ
Dammit!
Fullmetal Alchemist?
鋼の錬金術師
Kimblee!
キンブリー
Why the hell didn't you keep an eye on Winry?!
てめぇ  なんでちゃんと
ウィンリィを見てなかった
Mr. Kimblee, the roof!
キンブリーさん  屋上に
Even if we part and meet again, I want to meet at this place.
巡り巡ってもまたここで逢いたい
Megurimeguttemo mata koko de aitai
Then we'll hold hands to ensure we'll never be separated again.
はぐれないようにこの手をつなぐんだ
Hagurenaiyouni kono te wo tsunagunda
We used to talk all night until the sun rose,
朝日が昇るまで語り合ったね
Asahi ga noboru made katariattane
And held hands till the sun went under the horizon.
夕陽が沈むまでつないだ手
Yuuhi ga shizumu made tsunaida te
Let's walk together like this forever, like light and shadow.
こうやって明日も明後日も共に歩もう光と影
Kouyatte asu mo asatte mo tomo ni ayumou hikari to kage
I stand in the city, staring off into space with lonely eyes.
寂しげに見つめる街の中で
Samishige ni mitsumeru machi no naka de
I can't find warmth on my own.
温もりはひとりじゃ見つからなくて
Nukumori wa hitori ja mitsukaranakute
By meeting you, I realized
愛がこんなに強さになること
Ai ga konnani tsuyosa ni narukoto
How much strength love could give me.
知ったんだ　キミに出逢えてはじめて
Shittanda kimi ni deaete hajimete
Even if we part and meet again, I want to meet at this place.
巡り巡ってもまたここで逢いたい
Megurimeguttemo mata koko de aitai
Then we'll hold hands to ensure we'll never be separated again.
はぐれないようにこの手をつなぐんだ
Hagurenaiyouni kono te wo tsunagunda
I can't sleep by myself, 'cause I can't dream without you.
一人じゃ眠れない　夢は見れないから
Hitori ja nemurenai yume wa mirenaikara
So take me to a place where uncertainty can't reach us
どんな不安も届かないところへ
Donna fuan mo todokanai tokoro e
And let us bring light to the night sky with no stars.
星のない夜も照らし続けよう
Hoshi no yoru mo terashitsuzukeyou
So long as you're with me, I can go to world's end.
何処までも行けるキミとなら
Doko made mo yukeru kimi to nara
Even if it's a path I can't walk on my own,
一人じゃ歩けない道も二人なら
Hitori ja arukenai michi mo futari nara
If you're by my side, I can walk it while humming a tune.
鼻歌歌いながら歩けるんだ
Hanauta utainagara arukerunda
If we're together, the world is mine.
キミがいれば幸せ
Kimi ga ireba shiawase
日本語字幕仕上げ：XIAOBIN
悲しみを伴う出会いだとしても
Even if an encounter is accompanied by grief,
出会ったことには意味がある
there is still meaning in it.
漫遊字幕組
http://popgo.net/bbs
去来する感情にこそ
The path to take is inscribed in feelings that come and go.
進むべき道が記されている
Next time, Fullmetal Alchemist:
次回　鋼の錬金術師
Fullmetal  Alchemist
第３９話　「白昼の夢」
Episode 39, Daydream.
Is everything part of a plan devised by a superior being?